[SPEAKER_00]: So, you were saying earlier, what is interesting was that a person cannot get the right view without first abandoning the value of sensuality.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Abandoning the value of sensuality is not necessarily like abandoning sensuality, is it?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, that, that, that is what abandoning sensuality is.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's the root of it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Not, like, not performing sensual acts is not necessarily abandoning sensuality.
[SPEAKER_01]: You might be abstained from engaging with sensuality, like sexuality and so on.
[SPEAKER_01]: You might be restrained there and celibate, but you are not abandoning the value of sense pleasure, which means you're not free from sensuality, even if you're physically withdrawn from it, as the Buddha would say.
[SPEAKER_01]: But in those suttas we quoted in the past, where the Buddha would establish lay people or anybody else in the right view, that would be the thing.
[SPEAKER_01]: First, generosity, talk about the future life, goodness, and so on and so on, and then the Buddha would start talking and teaching them about the perils of sense desires.
[SPEAKER_01]: How little satisfaction they provide.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, in the nature, sensuality, he would teach about that.
[SPEAKER_01]: Ah, in its nature, sense desires are not worthy.
[SPEAKER_01]: In its nature, sense desires of any kind, engaging with sense pleasures and seeking them out, is unwholesome.
[SPEAKER_01]: Regardless of what extent, and this is acceptable.
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: In its nature, anything that pertains to the nature of sense desire, must be abandoned.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then, the right view would arise in those people.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then, you would teach them this is suffering, this is the origin of suffering and so on.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because for as long as you don't abandon the value of sense pleasures, you're preventing the necessary basis for the right view to be established.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, even if those people later on returned to sensuality, they never returned to the value of sensuality.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, they might have returned to sensuality if, you know, they had duties and circumstances taking them back and so on, but they never valued it again.
[SPEAKER_01]: Which means, every time you're back in sensuality, they would have felt ashamed, uncomfortable and unpleasant.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, they were still engaging with sense pleasures,
[SPEAKER_01]: Despite having the right view and so on, but that's because they were satisfied with the right view and they had many things to do, as they would say to the Buddha.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, I have to, excuse me now, you know, I have many things to do.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the Buddha would say, well, do as you see fit.
[SPEAKER_01]: But more often than not, actually, in the suttas, people, upon developing the right view, would ask to go forth.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because life that's rooted and revolves around sensual domain is meaningless.
[SPEAKER_01]: It always was meaningless, but now that whole thing became even more apparent.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, like, people would return to it when, you know, they had big responsibilities, people's lives depending on them and so on, then they couldn't just ignore it.
[SPEAKER_01]: But even then, there were a number of cases who returned and then continued practicing celibacy and looking after their wives because they made the promise they will.
[SPEAKER_01]: But they said, it's unfitting for me now to engage in a sexual intercourse with you.
[SPEAKER_01]: And so on.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, what is... what is the value?
[SPEAKER_01]: That's it.
[SPEAKER_01]: The value of pleasure that you get through your senses.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, the sense objects are not a problem.
[SPEAKER_01]: The senses are not a problem.
[SPEAKER_01]: Even the pleasures that arise on account of sense objects and senses are not the problem.
[SPEAKER_01]: You valuing them, desiring them, entertaining them, protecting them, delighting in them, that's the problem.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, you have to abandon the value of pleasure, which means you have to be willing to accept in that universal manner, that for the rest of your life, sense pleasure is bad not to be engaged with.
[SPEAKER_01]: If you, as I said before, if you fail to do it,
[SPEAKER_01]: You might fail, like, in your acts, as in you might, sort of, go back to sensuality, but you will not fail in establishing the value that sensuality is bad, which means whenever you fail in sustaining such acts of renunciation, you will feel guilty, you will feel ashamed.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, next time...
[SPEAKER_01]: They will protect you from doing it.
[SPEAKER_01]: But, they will not protect you from doing it if you never question the value of sense pleasures.
[SPEAKER_01]: If you basically, even before questioning it, you start defending it and justifying it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Means, you're never gonna uproot it, even if you live celibate for the rest of your life.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because you uproot sensuality by uprooting the value of pleasure, not by abstaining physically from it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Of course, abstaining physically from it is a necessary basis for you to see the value of it, and then you can uproot it.
[SPEAKER_01]: But in itself, it will not automatically result in it.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, the value of... of... Basically, it's like learning to see that... By the way, all the sense pleasures are addictive.
[SPEAKER_01]: The definition of addiction means definition of sense domain, sensual domain.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, all these different addictions share that same nature in themselves.
[SPEAKER_01]: They're sensual.
[SPEAKER_01]: They provide sense pleasure.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, obviously, sexuality and that kind of deeply rooted central needs are the greatest of all addictions.
[SPEAKER_01]: But as any other addiction, if you abstain from it, it will become more apparent for what it is.
[SPEAKER_01]: The only reason you're not seeing your addiction is because you refuse to give it up.
[SPEAKER_01]: But if you start having reasons for giving it up, then you get to see how really addicted you are.
[SPEAKER_01]: You're never going to see how addicted to cigarettes or heroin you are until you try and quit it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then you feel all the weight of it.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, the necessary step for giving up addiction is to give it up.
[SPEAKER_01]: Stop doing it.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's an act of will.
[SPEAKER_01]: Act of will to abstain yourself physically from engaging with it, and then the value of it will become more apparent.
[SPEAKER_01]: Which means you have to accept pure, unadulterated pain of withdrawal.
[SPEAKER_01]: That has to be the first step.
[SPEAKER_01]: And not just accept it for a week,
[SPEAKER_01]: For ten days, you have to accept it universally.
[SPEAKER_01]: You don't know how long it will last.
[SPEAKER_01]: It doesn't matter.
[SPEAKER_01]: Sensuality will never be valuable, even as something that could free you from that pain, which is kind of the inherent value of sensuality.
[SPEAKER_01]: Not just it provides you with pleasure, it provides you the only form of escape from pain that you know, as the Buddha said.
[SPEAKER_01]: Which means, even if you don't value sensual pleasures, like, you don't value objects of your senses, you value sensuality as the means of escape from discomfort.
[SPEAKER_01]: And that's already a wrong view.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's already a problem.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, if you accept then the value, or rather, if you see through the apparent value of sensuality, and see it as non-valuable, as something to not be delighted, something dangerous, something not worthy, all those descriptions the Buddha would talk about, and you have to accept then the pain that will come out of it, you kind of know it will not gonna last for the rest of your life, but see, hoping that it doesn't last for the rest of your life, means implicitly hoping that you can return back to sensuality.
[SPEAKER_01]: And you must never accept sensuality, even in the utmost remote future.
[SPEAKER_01]: The nature of sensuality is always perilous, always not worthy lighting in, always dangerous, which means, in this life and lives to come, any future, there will never be crossing between the domain of me wanting sensuality and being free from sensuality.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then you'll see, the pain might not even last that long.
[SPEAKER_01]: But you have to accept it as if it's gonna last forever.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because if you don't, to that extent, you're still valuing sensuality as freedom from pain.
[SPEAKER_01]: And all those passages we quoted in the past, that's exactly what he describes.
[SPEAKER_01]: He will make people understand the danger of the sense desires.
[SPEAKER_01]: Not this sense's desire, or half of that sense's desire.
[SPEAKER_01]: In its nature, the act of sense... chasing sense pleasure, going after sense... valuing sense pleasure, that's already why it's dangerous.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, you make people understand that.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, fully understanding it, abandoning it at that universal level, even if you physically remain still attracted and can lapse due to carelessness and go back to centrality, you'll never go back to the value of centrality.
[SPEAKER_01]: That would then dictate your whole life.
[SPEAKER_01]: Which is the case with most of the people.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, you've seen the extent
[SPEAKER_01]: The extent of gratification is the extent of what's valuable in sensuality for you.
[SPEAKER_01]: That is the extent of its gratification.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, you have to try and find out what's...
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, you have to understand why you are attracted to sensuality.
[SPEAKER_01]: Not in a psychologizing manner.
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, because my hormones... No, no, no.
[SPEAKER_01]: Why do you value, mentally, pleasures of the senses?
[SPEAKER_01]: Why can you just not value them?
[SPEAKER_01]: Oh, because you never try to not value them.
[SPEAKER_01]: You're always taking them for granted and valuing them for what they are.
[SPEAKER_01]: Pleasure is always regarded as good.
[SPEAKER_01]: Pleasure of senses.
[SPEAKER_01]: Only when it gets a bit excessive, you can say, okay, now it's a bit much.
[SPEAKER_01]: No, no.
[SPEAKER_01]: You don't want your value to depend on the quantity or even quality of the pleasure.
[SPEAKER_01]: Doesn't matter if it's lofty, as the Buddha said, if it's heavenly, if it's lowly, like animal realm.
[SPEAKER_01]: Doesn't matter if it's little, if it's a lot.
[SPEAKER_01]: Like, little bit of excrement smells as bad as the full truckload of it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Same with sensuality.
[SPEAKER_01]: Little bit of it shares the same nature of perilous, danger, not worth adhering to and engaging with.
[SPEAKER_01]: Doesn't matter how refined.
[SPEAKER_01]: And that's in that sutta the perfect types of celibacy that Buddha talks about.
[SPEAKER_01]: First is, you don't have sexual intercourse.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then, second, you don't touch women.
[SPEAKER_01]: You don't let them touch you.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then, you don't talk to them.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then, you don't go and listen to them.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then, you don't think about them.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then, you don't think about the pleasure of heavens and so on that you will get through such perfect restraint.
[SPEAKER_01]: If you withdraw yourself from all this wanting of this pleasure, that's the perfect celibacy, perfect brahmacharya, as the Buddha described it.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then, the only course left for you is to uproot your addiction to pleasure of any kind.
[SPEAKER_01]: And there is no way you would be able to re-evaluate the value of sensuality, unless you're first physically withdrawn from it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Unless you take on the sensory strength and the precepts.
[SPEAKER_01]: And really, we are talking about eight precepts.
[SPEAKER_01]: Five precepts is how you should live your life.
[SPEAKER_01]: They would separate you from an animal.
[SPEAKER_01]: But five precepts is not a basis for understanding.
[SPEAKER_01]: Five precepts is the lowest minimum threshold of a wholesome life.
[SPEAKER_01]: But that doesn't mean you can get wisdom on account of the minimum threshold of a wholesome life.
[SPEAKER_01]: But yes, if you haven't kept any precepts whatsoever, yeah, five is a good place to start.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, the value in sensuality is that it provides a gratification, a pleasure of some kind, of distracting myself from the fact that I am not satisfied.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, value of sensuality is that it provides you a pleasure from the pain of itself.
[SPEAKER_01]: Sensuality touches you with pain, but at the same time, it offers you solution for that pain.
[SPEAKER_01]: But... like, like racketeering.
[SPEAKER_01]: Hey, if you pay me, I'll make your problems go away.
[SPEAKER_01]: Problems that I put on you, so that you will pay me.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, it's a good example.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: So you get racketeered by your own sensuality, your own desires.
[SPEAKER_01]: And the more you pay, the more they're gonna come knocking, because they say, oh, he's susceptible.
[SPEAKER_01]: Let's push him, let's bleed him dry.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's exactly what sensuality does to you.
[SPEAKER_01]: Until you draw a line for yourself, and then endure the pain.
[SPEAKER_01]: But you're not making it worse, that's the thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's the thing people fear.
[SPEAKER_00]: If I stop going after these pleasures, sexual type pleasures, somehow something bad's going to happen, something really bad.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, because you're not just giving up this pleasure or that pleasure.
[SPEAKER_01]: By giving up value of sensuality, you're giving up the value of the entire world of sensuality, which means... and that's the nature of any addiction.
[SPEAKER_01]: The reason why addictions are hard to give up, you're not giving them up specifically.
[SPEAKER_01]: You're giving up the whole world you lived through them.
[SPEAKER_01]: Whether it's alcohol, cigarettes, drugs, doesn't matter.
[SPEAKER_01]: The reason they're pleasant is because you get to experience the whole world on the basis of that substance or that addiction or that pleasure.
[SPEAKER_01]: Heroin is not pleasant in itself.
[SPEAKER_01]: Experiencing the world through harrowing is where that pleasure comes from.
[SPEAKER_01]: That peace, undisturbed, the greatest, whatever it is that people would be addicted to, it's defined by the experience of the world on account of it.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's why you literally, basically, lose any and complete interest in the world.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because you stop feeling anything in regard to it, which is what we all want to do from the start.
[SPEAKER_01]: Everybody wants peace.
[SPEAKER_01]: Everybody wants non-disturbance.
[SPEAKER_01]: And now you found a substance that provides you with utmost pleasure, whereby nothing can disturb you for as long as the substance lasts.
[SPEAKER_01]: But you only get... that non-disturbance gets defined by the disturbance that doesn't disturb you anymore.
[SPEAKER_01]: And when I say the world defines it, I don't mean you need to go and seek it out.
[SPEAKER_01]: Your senses are your world.
[SPEAKER_01]: So your senses stop disturbing you.
[SPEAKER_01]: If you're high on drugs, for example.
[SPEAKER_01]: And that's why it gets so painful, the withdrawal from that sense pleasure.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's because you're withdrawing from the only world you know.
[SPEAKER_01]: So it feels like dying, more often than not.
[SPEAKER_01]: Same with cigarettes, by the way.
[SPEAKER_01]: You smoke a cigarette, you're literally inhaling the whole world through them, as Sartre described in his book.
[SPEAKER_01]: And it's absolutely true.
[SPEAKER_01]: Everything, everything that you've been doing, you've been doing on the basis of possibility of that pleasure, enduring of that pleasure.
[SPEAKER_01]: And imagine now,
[SPEAKER_01]: You want to also uproot sexual pleasure, which is far more rooted than any heroin or drug you can be addicted to.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, you will need to have a pretty strong reason for that.
[SPEAKER_01]: Otherwise, there's no way you'll succeed.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, that's what I mean, like, even if you don't succeed in doing it, you must not dilute the reasons for doing it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because if you do that, that, for sure, you will not succeed.
[SPEAKER_01]: If you start devaluing the non-value of sensuality, means you're automatically valuing sensuality.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, if you say, no, no, no, I don't need to be restrained and I can practice dhamma at the same time, means I don't need to basically abandon the value of sensuality and at the same time I can practice dhamma.
[SPEAKER_01]: What is dhamma?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, dhamma is the dispassion and freedom from sensuality.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, you're saying you cannot devalue centrality, and by not devaluing it, you are devaluing it.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's a plain, utter, direct contradiction.
[SPEAKER_01]: And that's what the Buddha said even to people who are not necessarily following his teachings, when they ask him what criteria should they use for good or bad.
[SPEAKER_01]: He says, whatever practice leads to dispassion, disenchantment, abandoning, renunciation, you should follow, you should value it.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's more valuable.
[SPEAKER_01]: You should do it.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, what?
[SPEAKER_01]: Celibacy or non-celibacy?
[SPEAKER_01]: Which one leads to dispassion?
[SPEAKER_01]: Sensory strain or non-sensory strain?
[SPEAKER_01]: Which one leads to disenchantment?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, the answer is straightforward.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now you can say, yeah, but it's too much for me.
[SPEAKER_01]: Okay, that's fine.
[SPEAKER_01]: You're too weak.
[SPEAKER_01]: You admit you're too weak and that's the necessary basis for developing strength, recognizing your weakness.
[SPEAKER_01]: But if you say, no, no, no, I don't need to be sensory strained, that's it.
[SPEAKER_01]: You just throw away the whole thing now.
[SPEAKER_01]: And you stay weak.
[SPEAKER_01]: Same, like people say, I can give up smoking whenever I want.
[SPEAKER_01]: But you can't want to give up smoking whenever you want.
[SPEAKER_01]: And without wanting to give up smoking, without removing the value of smoking, you will never give it up.
[SPEAKER_00]: I can stop smoking when I want to stop.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, but I can't want to stop, basically.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I can't want to stop.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yes, sensuality, I can be restrained, yeah, but you can't want to be restrained.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because if you can, you will take it on in that universal manner.
[SPEAKER_01]: Sensuality is never worth engaging with.
[SPEAKER_00]: I know it's bad, but I don't...
[SPEAKER_00]: I still think it's...
[SPEAKER_00]: But it's not that bad.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, it's not that bad.
[SPEAKER_01]: Exactly.
[SPEAKER_01]: I know it's not as valuable as it presents itself, but it's not that unvaluable either.
[SPEAKER_00]: I've got nothing else to replace it with.
[SPEAKER_01]: You're not seeing the danger of it.
[SPEAKER_01]: You're not seeing the peril.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I need something to replace.
[SPEAKER_01]: Exactly, which means I need something to replace the vacuum left by removing the content of that which I value.
[SPEAKER_01]: Which means you never devalue it, you just replace it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Replace one addiction with the other.
[SPEAKER_01]: You're still addicted.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: But then, maybe if I replace my addiction with a better addiction... Refine, refine my addiction.
[SPEAKER_00]: So instead of drugs, I turn to God.
[SPEAKER_01]: See, that's fine.
[SPEAKER_01]: As long as you don't ignore the value of your addiction.
[SPEAKER_01]: In other words, yes, let me replace my non-precept keeping with five precepts.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's still better.
[SPEAKER_01]: But let me not develop the view that five precepts will be enough for me to devalue my addiction, because it's not.
[SPEAKER_01]: So if you don't develop the view, then it's fine.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then you can refine your five precepts onto eight precepts.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then eight precepts to ten precepts, and so on.
[SPEAKER_01]: The common thread to all of that is you wanting to be free from the value of centrality.
[SPEAKER_01]: But if you replace five precepts, if you replace your non-precept with five precepts and say, that's it, see, I have accomplished the restraint, means no.
[SPEAKER_01]: And now you must affect that there is still a lot more to be done in order to uproot the value of centrality.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, yes, you can replace your addiction with God or whatever you want, but don't entertain the notion that you are completely free from addiction.
[SPEAKER_01]: And most people, like on Monday level, they don't do that.
[SPEAKER_01]: Remember, like, you saw that people would say, oh, once an addict, you remain an addict for the rest of your life.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's just a question of managing and not returning back to the addiction.
[SPEAKER_01]: Literally means you remain valuing sensuality for the rest of your life.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now, you recognize that particular forms of the essentiality are worse than the other, such as heroin or any other drugs, resulted in far great reaching adverse consequences, but you still value pleasure of senses.
[SPEAKER_01]: And for that, you need more than just the determination of I'll give up this drug or that drug.
[SPEAKER_01]: You need to understand that it has to pertain for the rest of your life, and it has to be seen in its nature as dangerous, not worthy, and that pleasure, it's actually pain.
[SPEAKER_01]: And then, you will be able to devalue it.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, there's that practice, common practice of a super-practice.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's there for devaluing.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's those things that you are attracted to.
[SPEAKER_01]: It can help you initially.
[SPEAKER_01]: Exactly.
[SPEAKER_01]: People don't see the nature of the value of pleasure, which means they only see the object of their pleasure.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, you start practicing sensory strength, you will still value the objects of your pleasure.
[SPEAKER_01]: Then, you might want to devalue them a bit by seeing them for what they really are.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's what the Subha is, showing you the unattractive basis of everything that you can find attractive.
[SPEAKER_01]: But a subha in itself, exactly, can also become a wrong thing then, because in itself it will not lead you to devalue your dependence on pleasure, which is not in sense objects, nor in your senses.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's in your attitude towards possibility of pleasure.
[SPEAKER_01]: Okay, I renounce these pleasures, because they're not good, but you still value other pleasures that might come along.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's what the Buddha means.
[SPEAKER_01]: You don't need to sit and think about pleasures of heaven and rationalize them.
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_01]: Just by implying that there are other pleasures worthy of adhering to, except these ones that you renounced, you establish yourself upon that value, which means it's not... sensuality is not devalued in that universal manner.
[SPEAKER_01]: Pleasure of any kind.
[SPEAKER_01]: Doesn't matter if I see things that are agreeable or disagreeable.
[SPEAKER_01]: What matters is pleasure that I get on account of it, and seeking them out on account of wanting that pleasure that comes from them.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, your dependence on your own pleasure of your own senses, it's completely gratuitous and internal, and not to be found in the world.
[SPEAKER_01]: It's just... you have... it's a view.
[SPEAKER_01]: You value the pleasure.
[SPEAKER_01]: You assume them as valuable.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's why we call it one of the upādānas.
[SPEAKER_01]: And that's why even a puthujjana can free himself from sensuality.
[SPEAKER_01]: If he were to find a good enough reason to see that any form of sexual activity, any form of sensual pleasure is always unwholesome, always bad, not to be welcomed, not to be engaged with, and stick to it, he would get to see the true nature of it, which is dangerous, not to be welcomed, not to be engaged.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, the only reason people engage with sensuality is because they don't see the
[SPEAKER_01]: The danger of it, of that same thing.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, the only reason a person enjoys this beautiful beverage, as the Sutta says, is because you don't understand that it's poisonous.
[SPEAKER_01]: If you understand that it's poisonous... By the way, poison is undetectable.
[SPEAKER_01]: So, what's the difference, then, between a poisonous drink, that you don't know it's poisonous, and that you know it's poisonous?
[SPEAKER_01]: It's the knowledge in regard to it that's different.
[SPEAKER_01]: You know that it's poisonous.
[SPEAKER_01]: The pleasure, the taste, has remained perfect.
[SPEAKER_01]: But you now completely don't want it.
[SPEAKER_01]: Because you know it's the poison.
[SPEAKER_01]: That pleasure is the poison.
[SPEAKER_01]: Not like there is a hidden poison that I can extract from the pleasure and still have the pleasure.
[SPEAKER_01]: Pleasure is the poison.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's it.
[SPEAKER_01]: You regard pleasure as a poison, or as a painful doubt, as the Buddha would say, you will lose any attraction towards it.
[SPEAKER_01]: How long you have to regard it like that?
[SPEAKER_01]: Well, you don't know.
[SPEAKER_01]: But you have to take it in the ultimate sense.
[SPEAKER_01]: Not like, yeah, let me do it for a week and become anāgāmī and then I have to...
[SPEAKER_01]: I can go back to my life or something.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's it.
[SPEAKER_01]: That's how you also get to learn from your sense restraint.
[SPEAKER_01]: Devalue things that need to be devalued, not just blindly adhere to it.